<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-14T19:00:36+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">NamakSwaadAnusar</title><subtitle>The official Namak Swaad Anusar Website where a buddling hobbyist chef brings together her recipes fro the betterment of mankind.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Instant Green Chilly Pickle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Instant-Green-chilly-pickle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Instant Green Chilly Pickle" /><published>2020-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Instant-Green-chilly-pickle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Instant-Green-chilly-pickle/">&lt;p&gt;An easy to make, super yummy green chilly pickle. Super healthy and a true accomplice to anything you can imagine having a pickle with. Beware, you might have more of the pickle than the actual dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100gm green chillies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tea spoon saunf (fennel seeds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.5 tea spoon methre/ methi dana (fenugreek seeds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.5 tea spoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tea spoon jeera (Cumine seeds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tea spoon sarson seeds (mustard seeds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 table spoon mustard oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 table spoons vinegar (white or any)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tea spoon haldi (turmeric)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tea spoon heeng (asafoetida)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;method&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash and dry green chillies. Remove danthal (stems).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a pan, heat the mustard oil till it starts smoking. After 30 seconds, turn off the gas and let it cool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut chillies into bite sized pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a kadhai, dry roast the saunf, methi dana, jeera, sarson seeds to remove moisture. Let it cool down naturally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind the roasted masalas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a glass bowl, add vinegar, mustard oil and all the dry masalas with salt. Mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chillies and mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This can be stored in the refrigerator for upto 6 months.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store in an airtight glass jar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t use wet or dirty spoon to take out pickle, it may lead to spoilage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">An easy to make, super yummy green chilly pickle. Super healthy and a true accomplice to anything you can imagine having a pickle with. Beware, you might have more of the pickle than the actual dish. Ingredients 100gm green chillies 3 tea spoon saunf (fennel seeds) 1.5 tea spoon methre/ methi dana (fenugreek seeds) 1.5 tea spoon salt 1 tea spoon jeera (Cumine seeds) 3 tea spoon sarson seeds (mustard seeds) 4 table spoon mustard oil 4 table spoons vinegar (white or any) 1 tea spoon haldi (turmeric) 1/4 tea spoon heeng (asafoetida) Method Wash and dry green chillies. Remove danthal (stems). In a pan, heat the mustard oil till it starts smoking. After 30 seconds, turn off the gas and let it cool. Cut chillies into bite sized pieces. In a kadhai, dry roast the saunf, methi dana, jeera, sarson seeds to remove moisture. Let it cool down naturally. Grind the roasted masalas. In a glass bowl, add vinegar, mustard oil and all the dry masalas with salt. Mix well. Add the chillies and mix well. Note This can be stored in the refrigerator for upto 6 months. Store in an airtight glass jar Don’t use wet or dirty spoon to take out pickle, it may lead to spoilage.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/instant-mirchi.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Coconut Coriander Chutney</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Coconut-coriander-chutney/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coconut Coriander Chutney" /><published>2020-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Coconut-coriander-chutney</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Coconut-coriander-chutney/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup fresh/ frozen cocnut&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup coriander leaves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 green chillies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 inch ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup roasted chana daal (fried gram)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tea spoon sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoon oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon mustard seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon urad dal (black gram)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinch heeng (asofoetida)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4-5 curry leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;method&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a blender, take coconut, coriander, roasted chana dal, ginger and green chillies and blend well with a little water till it forms a smooth paste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the chutney into a bowl, add salt, sugar and lemon juice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a pan, heat the oil, add mustard seeds and let them pop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add urad dal and saute till brown in color, turn off the stove, add heeng and curry leaves (this is your tadka).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the tadka to the chutney immediately and mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ingredients 1 cup fresh/ frozen cocnut 1 cup coriander leaves 2 green chillies 1/2 inch ginger 1/4 cup roasted chana daal (fried gram) Salt to taste 1/4 tea spoon sugar 2 teaspoons lemon juice 2 teaspoon oil 1/2 teaspoon mustard seeds 1/2 teaspoon urad dal (black gram) Pinch heeng (asofoetida) 4-5 curry leaves Method In a blender, take coconut, coriander, roasted chana dal, ginger and green chillies and blend well with a little water till it forms a smooth paste. Transfer the chutney into a bowl, add salt, sugar and lemon juice. In a pan, heat the oil, add mustard seeds and let them pop. Add urad dal and saute till brown in color, turn off the stove, add heeng and curry leaves (this is your tadka). Add the tadka to the chutney immediately and mix well.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Coconut-coriander-chutney.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Spinach Chicken</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spinach-chicken/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spinach Chicken" /><published>2019-01-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-01-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spinach-chicken</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spinach-chicken/">&lt;p&gt;A common and simple accompanyment to a typical north indian home cooked meal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;250gm palak (spinach)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;250gm chicken (cubes/ curry cut)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100gm dhaniya (coriander)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 onions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon garlic paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ginger paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 green chillies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoon curd&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoon ghee (solid)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon dhaniya powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 teaspoon jeera powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon haldi (turmeric)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon garam masala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;method&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind onion, garlic, ginger and chillies (onion paste).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blanch palak and dhaniya (put dhnaiya and boil the water, let it stay for aminute and then put spinach and blanch)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cool palak and dhaniya, grind and keep aside (don’t throw the water)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marinate chicken with curd and dhaniya powder, jeera powder, haldi, garam masala, salt (1/2 teaspoon) and keep aside for 30 mins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a kadai, add desi ghee, heat it and add onion paste. Saute till brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind tomatoes and saute till it leaves oil with the onion paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chicken and saute till it is tender (cook on low flame)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add palak to the cooked chicken and saute till dry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the palak water to the above (one karchi (serving spoon) at a time) till all the water finishes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with lacha parantha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A common and simple accompanyment to a typical north indian home cooked meal! Ingredients 250gm palak (spinach) 250gm chicken (cubes/ curry cut) 100gm dhaniya (coriander) 3 onions 1 teaspoon garlic paste 1 teaspoon ginger paste 2 green chillies 2 teaspoon curd 2 teaspoon ghee (solid) 1/2 teaspoon dhaniya powder 3/4 teaspoon jeera powder 1/2 teaspoon haldi (turmeric) 3 tomatoes 1/2 teaspoon garam masala Method Grind onion, garlic, ginger and chillies (onion paste). Blanch palak and dhaniya (put dhnaiya and boil the water, let it stay for aminute and then put spinach and blanch) Cool palak and dhaniya, grind and keep aside (don’t throw the water) Marinate chicken with curd and dhaniya powder, jeera powder, haldi, garam masala, salt (1/2 teaspoon) and keep aside for 30 mins. In a kadai, add desi ghee, heat it and add onion paste. Saute till brown. Grind tomatoes and saute till it leaves oil with the onion paste Add chicken and saute till it is tender (cook on low flame) Add palak to the cooked chicken and saute till dry. Add the palak water to the above (one karchi (serving spoon) at a time) till all the water finishes. Serve with lacha parantha.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/methi-thepla.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Methi Thepla</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/methi-thepla/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Methi Thepla" /><published>2019-01-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-01-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/methi-thepla</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/methi-thepla/">&lt;p&gt;A common and simple accompanyment to a typical north indian home cooked meal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup methi (fenugreek) leaves tightly packed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;120 gm aata (whole wheat flour)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup (40 gm) besan (gram flour)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup (40 gm) bajra (pearl millet) {optional}&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup (40 gm) jowar (sorghum) {optional}&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 inch / 1 tea spoon adrak (ginger)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon / 2 pieces green chillies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon red chilly powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon haldi (turmeric)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon jeera powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon dhaniya powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 teaspoon salt (or to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4-5 tbsp yogurt or water for kneading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oil for roasting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;method&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rinse and drain methi, chop finely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the dough, in a bowl take 1 cup whole wheat flour, besan, bajra and jowar. If you don’t have bajra and jowar, just add 1.25 cups of aata and 1/2 cup besan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add all dry herbs and spices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now add curd and knead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t add water with methi leaves while kneading (they release water). Add curd if required&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With the dough, make small balls and, using a rolling pin, roll out as chapatis but thinner. On a hot tawa, cook the thepla, generously adding oil (so they remain soft).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with curd or green chilly pickle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A common and simple accompanyment to a typical north indian home cooked meal! Ingredients 1 cup methi (fenugreek) leaves tightly packed 120 gm aata (whole wheat flour) 1/4 cup (40 gm) besan (gram flour) 1/4 cup (40 gm) bajra (pearl millet) {optional} 1/4 cup (40 gm) jowar (sorghum) {optional} 1/2 inch / 1 tea spoon adrak (ginger) 1/2 teaspoon / 2 pieces green chillies 1/2 teaspoon red chilly powder 1/2 teaspoon haldi (turmeric) 1/2 teaspoon jeera powder 1/2 teaspoon dhaniya powder 3/4 teaspoon salt (or to taste) 1 tbsp oil 4-5 tbsp yogurt or water for kneading Oil for roasting Method Rinse and drain methi, chop finely. For the dough, in a bowl take 1 cup whole wheat flour, besan, bajra and jowar. If you don’t have bajra and jowar, just add 1.25 cups of aata and 1/2 cup besan. Add all dry herbs and spices Now add curd and knead Don’t add water with methi leaves while kneading (they release water). Add curd if required With the dough, make small balls and, using a rolling pin, roll out as chapatis but thinner. On a hot tawa, cook the thepla, generously adding oil (so they remain soft). Serve with curd or green chilly pickle.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/methi-thepla.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jeera Aloo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Jeera-Aloo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jeera Aloo" /><published>2018-01-12T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Jeera-Aloo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Jeera-Aloo/">&lt;p&gt;A common and simple accompanyment to a typical north indian home cooked meal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 large boiled potatoes diced in 1 inch pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tea spoon jeera (cumin seeds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 table spoons oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tea spoon red chilly powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 table spoon coriender seeds crushed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tea spoon roasted cumine powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tea spoon amchur (dry mango powder)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 table spoons fresh coriender leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;method&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat oil in a pan and add cumin seeds and saute till it stops crackling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add salt and stir&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add red chilly powder, crushed coriender seeds, raosted cumin powder and amchur.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add potato cubes and stir carefully till the masala covers all the potato cubes well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the coriender leaves and stir.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve hot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A common and simple accompanyment to a typical north indian home cooked meal! Ingredients 4 large boiled potatoes diced in 1 inch pieces 1 tea spoon jeera (cumin seeds) 4 table spoons oil Salt to taste 1 tea spoon red chilly powder 1 table spoon coriender seeds crushed 1 tea spoon roasted cumine powder 1/2 tea spoon amchur (dry mango powder) 2 table spoons fresh coriender leaves Method Heat oil in a pan and add cumin seeds and saute till it stops crackling. Add salt and stir Add red chilly powder, crushed coriender seeds, raosted cumin powder and amchur. Add potato cubes and stir carefully till the masala covers all the potato cubes well. Add the coriender leaves and stir. Serve hot.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/jeera-aloo.jpg" /></entry></feed>